

Wayne Brendin Kobusch Curriculum Vitae

PROFILE

» Hospitality Executive » CEO/COO » Entrepreneur

VISION

To utilise my professional acumen and experience in enhancing • shareholder value.

EXECUTIVE SUMMARY

Astute and globally enlightened Hospitality Management Executive, Real Estate, Entrepreneur and CEO with over 30 years' experience managing various high-end resorts, property developments and hotels in the United Arab Emirates and South Africa.

Currently, I am the Operations Advisor to the Group CEO of Al Forsan Holdings LLC, which includes Al Forsan International Sports Resort, Al Forsan Real Estate (consisting of 385 deluxe villas), Al Forsan 5* Hotel (managed by Marriott International) and Al Forsan Retail Mall, in Abu Dhabi.

A versatile business professional with entrepreneurial flair, I own and manage Wood-Moore Manor Stud, a horserace breeding company formed in 2006. Prior to that I worked for 18 years at General Manager PERSONAL SKILLS level for reputable hospitality brands that included Abu Dhabi Golf and Equestrian Club, Dainfern Country Club & Golfing, Residential Estate and • The Lost City (Sun City).

I have all-round business management acumen with solid pedigree in the areas of business strategy development and execution, marketing, social media management, business development, profit and loss management, food and beverage management, business operations management, finance, front office, product, people, training and service quality management, standard operating procedures, key performance indicators.

Affable and diplomatic, I interact well with people from diverse backgrounds. My amiable personality, vocal ability and natural love for people are my main strengths, whilst paying attention to bottom line profitability, I feel that any organisation can benefit tremendously from these skills.

PERSONAL DETAILS

Currently located in Abu Dhabi, UAE akh3005@gmail.com Mobile: +971547588997

Gender: Male Nationality: South Africa

Interests: Hospitality, leisure & equestrian

sports

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Leadership, Motivation and Mentorship
- Strategic Business Management
- Entrepreneurship
- Product Development and Management
- Project Management (*Opened 3, 5 Star Hotels)
- Marketing Management
- Social Media Management
- **Hotel Operations Management**
- Food and Beverage Management
- Revenue and Financial Management
- Service Quality Management
- Training and Development
- Toastmasters International CTM
- NQ Steering Committee Chairman
- **Key Performance Indicators**
- Policy definition and standard operating procedure creation
- On The Job Skills Development & Training

QUALIFICATIONS

- Diploma in Hotel Management SA Hotel Board and SA Tourism Board
- Diploma in Business Management, Damelin College
- Chef du Rang and Chef de Table Chaine des Rotisseurs

- Integrity
- Honesty
- Collaborative
- Driven
- Focused
- Strategic
- Analytical

LEADERSHIP ROLES

- Past Main Board Director of Gold Circle Gaming and Leisure
 - Member of Audit and Risk Committees
- Past Vice Chairman of KZN Racing Chapter (South
- Past Board Member KZN Breeders Club

COMPUTER SKILLS

MS Office Suite Packages, Fidelio, Micros

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Position: Operations Advisor to Group CEO
Company: Al Forsan Holdings LLC, Abu Dhabi

Period: July 2020 to current

Scope of Work Done:

As an advisor to the CEO, my current responsibilities include:

- Develop and implement business strategy
- Create and standardise new operating manuals, with policies and procedures across the group (SOPs), and ensure implementation thereof
- Set tangible goals for performance and growth with benchmark KPIs
- Strategic development, and budgeting for 2020/21 financial year.
- Oversee strategic and operational standards, ensuring delivery of all, within the activities and facilities at Al Forsan
- Develop and implement business strategy, plans and procedures.
- Set goals for performance and growth.
- Motivate staff to encourage maximum performance and meet targets.
- Build and maintain trusted relationships with key customers, clients, partners and stakeholders.
- Manage risk and crisis issues.
- Facilitated the closure of all outstanding audit reports retrospective to 2017.
- Developed and created expansion activities as well as new product lines and revenue centers.
- Evaluate effectiveness and efficiency of operational systems, technology and delivery processes.
- Identify improvement areas and overseeing change management initiatives across the business.
- Ensure effective recruiting, professional development, performance management, and retention.
- Direct acquisitions and sales of assets to meet organization goals.
- Adhere to all regulatory requirements, enforcing compliance and taking action when necessary.
- Apply best business practice, ethics and corporate governance.
- Prepare brief's for legal counsel in terms of third party contract breaches in the Real Estate area.

This was part of the turnaround strategy for the group to increase revenues, products, services and ultimately return on investment. (ROI)

Position: General Manager

Company: Al Forsan International Sports Resort (www.alforsan.com)

Period: June 2019 to June 2020

Scope of Work Done:

- Create and implement a turnaround strategy for the resort to increase revenues, product and services
 - Effectively manage a team across revenue generators including, Equestrian, Extreme Sports, Food and Beverage, Go karting, Shooting and Water Sports.
 - Ensure client creation, retention and satisfaction
 - Integrated and automated the Front Office back office ERP system from the previous manual process
 - Successfully reduced internal audit points that had been outstanding for more than three years
 - Define policies and create standard operating procedures across the organisation
 - Setting new benchmark Key Performance Indicators (300 Employees) based on strategy and budget
 - Budget creation for revenue and cost centres
 - Effective cash flow management

Position: CEO/Owner

Company: Wood-Moore Manor Stud **Period:** August 2006 to current

Scope of Work Done:

- Breeding Tomorrows Legends Today!
- Raise and maintain awareness of brand on social media
- Networking within the racing industry with important stakeholders
- Breed the most commercial horse you can afford
- Empowering staff and aligning their interests with our own

Position: Club Managing Director

Company: Abu Dhabi Golf and Equestrian Club, Abu Dhabi, UAE

Period: July 2001 – July 2006

Scope of Work Done:

Implement strategic business plan with approved budgets across revenue classes

- Focus on customer satisfaction, financial controls whilst ensuring return on investments for the shareholders
- Improved golf course standards and Food and Beverage outlets

Position: General Club Manager (<u>www.dainfern.co.za</u>)

Company: Dainfern Country Club & Golfing, Residential Estate

Period: December 1997 – March 2001

Scope of Work Done:

- Premier benchmark residential estate with Gary Player designed golf course *1 572 homes
- Took a loss-making business and increased revenue; customer satisfaction and with an improved balance sheet recapitalised the venue.

Position: Director Food and Beverage

Company: The Lost City, Sun City, 5* Deluxe Resort

Period: August 1996 – November 1997

Scope of Work Done:

- · Largest Food and Beverage Operation in the Southern Hemisphere
- Management of 28 restaurants and 45 theme bars including the 7* Palace Hotel, The Gary Player Golf Course at the Lost City, Valley of the Waves, Entertainment Centre and Casino, as well as the 5* Cascades Hotel
- Banqueting for up to 5 000 people (Miss World Pageant, Michael Jackson Concert, Elton Jon Concert, Annual Nedbank Million Dollar Golf Challenge)
 - Set-up and breakdown of the entire event, closely monitoring the progress of exhibitor stand builds. Great attention to detail was vital when cross-checking set-up with the signage plan throughout the venues, including the Superbowl.
 - On ground management of information desk team, including staff briefing and familiarization tour. Time
 management and planning of team shifts and break rotation to ensure each desk was staffed throughout the
 event.
 - Ability to multi-task with numerous sponsored lunches, desserts, and coffee breaks taking place on different days and on different floors of the venue. Ensuring the staff was properly briefed on the set-up requirements.
 - Daily briefings with client and sales and marketing team and operational staff
- Chairman of the NQ Steering Committee and Implementation of standardising all operating manuals, policies and procedures throughout the entire resort, including the Sun City Main Hotel, Cabanas Sun City Casino and Vacation Club.

Position: General Manager Country Club

Company: Anglo American Platinum/JCI - Rustenburg

Period: July 1993 – July 1996

Position: Assistant Club Manager

Company: Hans Merensky Golf Course and Real Estate Development (Rio Tinto/Palaborwa Mining Company)

Period: December 1992 – July 1993

Position: Special Projects Manager / Rooms Division Manager / Food & Beverage Manager

Company: Lord Charles Hotel 5* Deluxe Hotel
Period: August 1988 – December 1992

Scope of Work Done:

- Pre-opening Management team
- Food and Beverage
- Promoted to Rooms Division/Front Office
- Promoted to Special Projects Manager/Sales and Marketing

REFERENCES Available on request